I bow to all the seekers of truth.
أنحني لجميع الباحثين عن الحقيقة.
At the very outset we have to know that truth is
في البداية علينا أن نعرف أن الحقيقة هي
what it is. We cannot organize it, we cannot mold it. Also we cannot know it at the stage
ما هي عليه.  لا يمكننا تنظيمه، ولا يمكننا تشكيله.  كما أننا لا نستطيع أن نعرفها في المرحلة
when we are human beings, with human awareness we cannot know it. So we have to become a
التي نكون فيها بشر، بالوعي الإنساني لا نستطيع أن نعرفها.  لذلك علينا أن نصبح
super human being, a higher personality. What is said that you have to be the Spirit, you
إنسانًا خارقًا، وشخصية عليا.  ما يقال أنه عليك أن تكون الروح،
have to be the Self. In all the scriptures, in all the religions it has been said that
عليك أن تكون الذات.  لقد قيل في جميع الكتب المقدسة، وفي جميع الأديان، أنه
you have to be the Spirit. I mean we see the turmoil and the problems of the world that
عليك أن تكون الروح.  أعني أننا نرى الاضطرابات ومشاكل العالم التي
are completely show us clearly that there is so much of a mess and most of them are
تظهر لنا بوضوح تام أن هناك الكثير من الفوضى ومعظمها
the problems created by human beings. We have to do some introspection and some soul searching
مشاكل خلقها البشر.  علينا أن نقوم ببعض الاستبطان وبعض البحث عن النفس
and we have to find out, after all, why we human beings have created all these problems
وعلينا أن نكتشف، بعد كل شيء، لماذا خلقنا نحن البشر كل هذه المشاكل
for ourselves. We have had philosophies, we have ideologies, we have so many kinds of
لأنفسنا.  لقد كانت لدينا فلسفات، ولدينا أيديولوجيات، ولدينا أنواع كثيرة من
enterprises but despite that there are so many differences and the differences are having
المؤسسات، ولكن على الرغم من ذلك، هناك الكثير من الاختلافات، والاختلافات بها
larger and larger gaps. If it is the truth, it has to be the truth for everyone. Everyone
فجوات أكبر وأكبر.  إذا كانت هذه هي الحقيقة، فيجب أن تكون الحقيقة للجميع.  وعلى الجميع أن
has to say: "This is The Truth". But it has to be the Absolute Truth. If it is not the
يقول: "هذه هي الحقيقة".  ولكن يجب أن تكون الحقيقة المطلقة.  إذا لم تكن
Absolute Truth then what we believe into is not the reality. And this is the main reason
الحقيقة المطلقة فإن ما نؤمن به ليس هو الواقع.  وهذا هو السبب الرئيسي
why everything in the name of God, Divinity, everything has failed so far because it is
وراء فشل كل شيء باسم الله، الألوهية، كل شيء حتى الآن لأنه
not substantiated by reality.
لا يؤيده الواقع.
First we must feel the reality. And what is the reality, and what is the truth? The truth
أولا يجب أن نشعر بالواقع.  وما هو الواقع، وما هي الحقيقة؟  الحقيقة
is that you are the Spirit, you are the pure Spirit. And that there is All Pervading Power
هي أنك أنت الروح، أنت الروح النقي.  وأن هناك كل قوة
of divine love which does all living work. Now we see all these beautiful flowers, beautifully
المحبة الإلهية السائدة التي تقوم بكل العمل الحي. الآن نرى كل هذه الزهور الجميلة، مرتبة بشكل جميل
arranged, everything, but we never think how so many flowers have come out of one seed.
، كل شيء، لكننا لا نفكر أبدًا في عدد الزهور التي خرجت من بذرة واحدة.
How it has worked? This living work is done by whom? We will say: "The Mother Earth".
كيف عملت؟  من يقوم بهذا العمل الحي ؟  سنقول: "الأرض الأم".
But the Mother Earth seems to be just... just a thing... it is just a matter. Than how these
لكن يبدو أن أمنا الأرض مجرد... مجرد شيء... إنها مجرد مسألة.  فكيف
flowers have sprouted from a little seed, who has done this work? We don't even think
نبتت هذه الزهور من بذرة صغيرة، من قام بهذا العمل؟  ولا نفكر حتى
who has done the job of making us human beings from ameba stage. So for a hypothesis let
من الذي قام بمهمة جعلنا بشراً من مرحلة الأميبا.  لذا، بالنسبة للفرضية،
us think there is something, some power that is doing it. As scientists you must keep your
دعونا نعتقد أن هناك شيئًا ما، قوة ما تفعل ذلك.  كعلماء يجب أن تبقي
minds open. There is no use having blind faith in Me, in Sahaja Yoga, in anything because
عقولكم مفتوحة.  ليس هناك فائدة من الإيمان الأعمى بي، في ساهاجا يوغا، في أي شيء لأن
blindness will never give you reality. But you should be open like scientists are and
العمى لن يمنحك الحقيقة أبدًا.  لكن يجب أن تكون منفتحًا مثل العلماء، وأيًا
whatever hypothesis I am putting before you, you have to feel it on your central nervous
كانت الفرضية التي أطرحها أمامك، عليك أن تشعر بها على جهازك العصبي المركزي
system.
.
This is what is the Bouddha, is what is Buddha preached about that you have to feel the All
هذا هو البوذا، وهو ما بشر به بوذا، حيث يجب عليك أن تشعر بكل
Pervading Power on your central nervous system. And the time has come. Time has come for all
القوة المتغلغلة في جهازك العصبي المركزي.  وقد حان الوقت.  لقد حان الوقت
of you to feel that. You all can feel that All Pervading Power, the power of the Holy
لكم جميعا أن تشعروا بذلك.  يمكنكم جميعًا أن تشعروا بكل القوة السائدة، قوة
Ghost, power of the Primordial Mother. And then, once you are in connection with that,
الروح القدس، قوة الأم البدائية.  وبعد ذلك، بمجرد أن تكون على اتصال بذلك،
like this instrument when it is connected to the mains it has a meaning, your self-knowledge
مثل هذه الآلة عندما تكون متصلة بالتيار الكهربائي يكون لها معنى، فإن معرفتك الذاتية
will tell you what is the meaning of your life. Otherwise, there is no meaning. We are
ستخبرك ما هو معنى حياتك.  وإلا فلا معنى.  نحن
without any connections to the reality and that's why we do not know where are we drifting,
لا نملك أية صلة بالواقع، ولهذا السبب لا نعرف إلى أين ننجرف،
what is happening to us, where are we going. Now, I verily say to you that within us lies
وماذا يحدث لنا، وإلى أين نتجه. والآن، الحق أقول لكم إن في داخلنا تكمن
this instrument. And this instrument is very well intact in all of you.
هذه الأداة.  وهذه الأداة سليمة جدًا فيكم جميعًا.
Now, there are some people who have written books after books which have
الآن، هناك بعض الأشخاص الذين كتبوا كتبًا بعد الكتب التي صدمتني
really shocked Me saying that
حقًا قائلين إن
is very dangerous to raise the Kundalini, some people have said that
رفع الكونداليني أمر خطير للغاية، وقال بعض الأشخاص إن
Kundalini is in the stomach - shows they are unauthorized people or perhaps they do not
الكونداليني في المعدة - يظهر أنهم أشخاص غير مرخص لهم أو ربما لا
want you to have your self-knowledge, they want to deviate you. Also you will find people
يريدونك  لكي يكون لديك معرفة بذاتك، فإنهم يريدون أن يحيدوك.  ستجد أيضًا أشخاصًا
who will tell you that you should not do this Kundalini awakening and all that because very
سيخبرونك أنه لا ينبغي عليك القيام بصحوة الكونداليني وكل ذلك لأنه
dangerous and this brings problem. Not at all. This Kundalini which is in three and
خطير جدًا وهذا يسبب مشكلة. مُطْلَقاً.  هذه الكونداليني الموجودة في ثلاثة
a half coil is an energy of Pure desire within you. All other desires rise within us and
ملفات ونصف هي طاقة الرغبة النقية بداخلك .  كل الرغبات الأخرى ترتفع فينا وبمجرد
once we achieve them we still are not satisfied we are going from one desire to another. So
أن نحققها فإننا لا نزال غير راضين وننتقل من رغبة إلى أخرى.  لذا فإن
the law of economics is that in general desires are not satiable.
قانون الاقتصاد ينص على أن الرغبات بشكل عام غير قابلة للإشباع.
So this is the only power which has to rise and give us that Pure desire that once we
إذن هذه هي القوة الوحيدة التي يجب أن تنهض وتمنحنا تلك الرغبة النقية التي بمجرد أن نحققها
achieve it or once we manifest it then all the desires become absolutely of no value.
أو نظهرها تصبح كل الرغبات بلا قيمة على الإطلاق.
Then this madness of desire goes away and we understand all this transitory things,
ثم يختفي جنون الرغبة هذا ونفهم كل هذه الأشياء العابرة،
all this pleasures of life with it's full limitations and we know how far to go with
كل متع الحياة بحدودها الكاملة ونعرف إلى أي مدى سنذهب معهم
them.
.
But first we must seek the Eternal, we must seek this All Pervading Power which is very
لكن علينا أولاً أن نسعى إلى الأبدي، يجب أن نسعى إلى هذه القوة الشاملة التي هي
subtle and is all around us. But as human beings are as you must have seen here also,
خفية للغاية وتحيط بنا في كل مكان.  ولكن بما أن البشر هم كما رأيت هنا أيضًا، فإن
on top of your head here is on one side is the yellow ego; on the left side is your superego
أعلى رأسك هنا على جانب واحد هو الأنا الصفراء؛  على الجانب الأيسر توجد الأنا العليا الخاصة بك
- is your conditionings. We have so many conditionings in our mind. To say that I am an Indian and
- وهي تكييفاتك.  لدينا الكثير من التكييفات في أذهاننا.  أن أقول إنني هندي وأنت
you are British or you are this and you are that is a conditioning. God never created
بريطاني أو أنت هذا وأنت ذاك هو تكييف.  لم يخلق الله
world like that, He created only one world. We have made it like this. This is the one
عالمًا كهذا أبدًا، بل خلق عالمًا واحدًا فقط.  لقد جعلناها مثل هذا.  هذا
world, this is another world, this is another nation. We human beings have done - created
عالم، وهذا عالم آخر، وهذه أمة أخرى.  لقد فعلنا نحن البشر - خلقنا
problem for us. Of course, I mean He did create rivers and mountains and He did create different
مشكلة بالنسبة لنا.  بالطبع، أعني أنه خلق الأنهار والجبال، وخلق
type of people otherwise we all would have looked like some military junta. But no He
أنواعًا مختلفة من الناس، وإلا كنا سنبدو مثل طغمة عسكرية.  لكن لا، لقد
made us differently to look different. That was His idea to create beauty. Why we have
جعلنا مختلفين لنبدو مختلفين.  تلك كانت فكرته في خلق الجمال.  لماذا لدينا
such conditionings, from the very childhood we have conditionings of this kind, then we
مثل هذه الظروف، منذ الطفولة لدينا ظروف من هذا النوع، ثم نعتقد أننا
think we are born in a particular religion. So that is one another horrible conditioning
ولدنا في دين معين. إذن هذا هو التكييف الرهيب لبعضنا البعض
we have that we have got we are in this religion so we must follow this religion. But in Sahaja
الذي حصلنا عليه ونحن في هذا الدين لذا يجب علينا أن نتبع هذا الدين.  ولكن في ساهاجا
Yoga when you come you will be amazed to see that those people who started all these religions
يوجا عندما تأتي ستندهش عندما ترى أن هؤلاء الأشخاص الذين بدأوا كل هذه الديانات
are the real people and once they started it after some time is drifted into something
هم الأشخاص الحقيقيون وبمجرد أن بدأوا ذلك بعد مرور بعض الوقت انجرفوا إلى شيء
extremely nonsensical and now running away from religion also you can not solve the problem
لا معنى له على الإطلاق والآن يهربون من الدين أيضًا لا يمكنك حله  المشكلة
or running towards is just the same. So what is it that you have to go beyond all these
أو الركض نحو هو نفسه.  إذًا ما الذي يجب عليك أن تتجاوز كل هذه
conditionings that are there and also beyond your ego.
الشروط الموجودة هناك وأيضًا ما هو أبعد من غرورك.
Now, the ideas about ego are also prevalent and people say that these are our karmas,
الآن، الأفكار حول الأنا منتشرة أيضًا ويقول الناس أن هذه هي الكارما الخاصة بنا، ويجب
we must suffer. I know of so many people who say that: "Mother what about karmas". Now,
علينا أن نعاني.  أعرف الكثير من الأشخاص الذين يقولون: "يا أمي، ماذا عن الكارما".  الآن،
the yellow stuff that you see there is the ego, is the only human beings think that they
الأشياء الصفراء التي ترونها هناك هي الأنا، هي البشر الوحيدون الذين يعتقدون أنهم
have done some bad karmas or good karmas. Animals don't think. They are under the complete
ارتكبوا بعض الكارما السيئة أو الكارما الجيدة. الحيوانات لا تفكر.  إنهم تحت
control of God that's why they are called as pashu means paash - completely controlled.
سيطرة الله الكاملة ولهذا السبب يطلق عليهم اسم باشو وتعني باش - تحت السيطرة الكاملة.
A dog is a dog, a scorpion is a scorpion and tiger is a tiger. They behave the way they
الكلب كلب، والعقرب عقرب، والنمر نمر.  إنهم يتصرفون كما
are, but human beings are everything in them. You may find somebody as a very nice dog and
هم، لكن البشر هم كل شيء فيهم. قد تجد شخصًا ما كلبًا لطيفًا جدًا
suddenly becomes a snake. From where does it come in? It comes because still all these
ويصبح فجأة ثعبانًا.  ومن أين يأتي؟  يأتي ذلك لأنه لا تزال كل هذه
conditionings that are within us are built in and then also this ego that has come into
الشروط الموجودة في داخلنا مدمجة في هذه الأنا التي دخلت
us that I am doing this work, I am doing that work. Now, see we have a beautiful hall of
إلينا بأنني أقوم بهذا العمل، وأنا أقوم بهذا العمل.  الآن، نرى أن لدينا قاعة جميلة
course to be appreciated very much and we should say that it's a very good piece of
بالطبع تستحق التقدير كثيرًا ويجب أن نقول إنها قطعة فنية جيدة جدًا
art or whatever it is. But something like a tree was dead, so we have made this platform
أو أيًا كانت.  ولكن شيء مثل الشجرة قد مات، لذلك قمنا بتحويل هذه المنصة
from dead to dead. We have done no living work whatsoever, we cannot do it. But when
من ميتة إلى ميتة.  لم نقم بأي عمل حي على الإطلاق، ولا يمكننا القيام به.  ولكن عندما
the Kundalini rises you will be surprised in many people who have problems on their
ترتفع الكونداليني سوف تتفاجأ في كثير من الأشخاص الذين لديهم مشاكل في
centers you can see with naked eyes the pulsation
مراكزهم يمكنك أن ترى بالعين المجردة النبض
and on your hand you can see the pulsation
وعلى يدك يمكنك أن ترى نبض
of the Kundalini rising and you can feel the pulsation on top of your head here. And when
الكونداليني يرتفع ويمكنك أن تشعر بالنبض فوق رأسك  هنا.  وعندما
the pulsation disappears you feel the cool breeze coming out of your head, out of your
يختفي النبض تشعر بالنسيم البارد يخرج من رأسك، من
own head. All these things are to be verified. There cannot be pretensions about it, reality
رأسك.  كل هذه الأمور يجب التحقق منها. لا يمكن أن تكون هناك ادعاءات بشأن ذلك، فالواقع
stands by itself, it does not need any support. So when all this happens to you, what you
قائم بذاته، ولا يحتاج إلى أي دعم. لذلك عندما يحدث لك كل هذا، فإن ما
get- the self-knowledge.
تحصل عليه هو معرفة الذات.
And what is the self-knowledge is to first of all to know about your own centers. Now,
وما هي معرفة الذات أن تعرف أولاً عن مراكزك الخاصة.  والآن،
a person gets lunatic without knowing that he is getting lunatic, a person gets cancer
يصاب الإنسان بالجنون دون أن يعلم أنه مصاب بالجنون، ويصاب الإنسان بالسرطان
without knowing he has got cancer. Whatever happens to him, he does not know what is happening
دون أن يعلم أنه مصاب بالسرطان.  ومهما حدث له فهو لا يعلم ما يحدث
to him. He has to go to doctors, spend lot of money, everything and then the doctor certifies
له.  عليه أن يذهب إلى الأطباء، وينفق الكثير من المال، وكل شيء، ثم يؤكد الطبيب أنه
no you have these ten diseases in you and that now you will die after one month or so.
لا يوجد لديك هذه الأمراض العشرة وأنك الآن ستموت بعد شهر واحد أو نحو ذلك.
You don't know how it has developed in you, how it has come suddenly to you but when these
أنت لا تعرف كيف تطورت فيك، وكيف وصلت إليك فجأة، ولكن عندما تكون هذه
centers are out of gear then you feel this is wrong with you, that is wrong with you.
المراكز خارج نطاق العمل، فإنك تشعر أن هذا خطأ فيك، وهذا خطأ فيك.
Because you are realized soul and you can feel it on your fingertips when the centers
لأنك روح مدركة ويمكنك أن تشعر بها على أطراف أصابعك عندما
tell you that this is wrong with you. This is not only on physical side, physical side
تخبرك المراكز أن هذا خطأ فيك.  هذا ليس فقط على الجانب الجسدي، الجانب الجسدي
is the minimum that you get, but you find out about emotional side, you find out about
هو الحد الأدنى الذي تحصل عليه، لكنك تكتشف الجانب العاطفي، وتكتشف
your spiritual side also very clearly that spiritually where are you. Just to certify
جانبك الروحي أيضًا بشكل واضح جدًا أين أنت روحيًا.  فقط لتشهد
yourself that we are twice-born people or we are this and this is misleading yourself.
لنفسك أننا ولدنا مرتين أو أننا هذا وهذا تضليل لنفسك.
You've not been kind to yourself, I should say, and not honest to yourself.
يجب أن أقول إنك لم تكن لطيفًا مع نفسك، ولم تكن صادقًا مع نفسك.
We have to be honest, we have to find the truth and we have to get to it, because it
علينا أن نكون صادقين، علينا أن نجد الحقيقة وعلينا أن نصل إليها، لأنها
is our own, this is our right to have it as human beings and you cannot pay for it. One
حقنا، وهذا حقنا في الحصول عليها كبشر ولا يمكنك دفع ثمنها.
thing if you understand you cannot pay for it, you will understand what is reality. Like
شيء واحد إذا فهمت أنك لا تستطيع دفع ثمنه، فسوف تفهم ما هو الواقع.  مثل
the seed you plant in the Mother Earth. How much do we pay to Mother Earth? How much did
البذرة التي تزرعها في أمك الأرض. كم ندفع لأمنا الأرض؟  كم
we pay to Christ? How much did you pay to Rama or Krishna? To any one of them how much
دفعنا للمسيح؟  كم دفعت لراما أو كريشنا؟  لأي واحد منهم كم
did we pay? But those who are now commercialized all these ideas we are just getting lost into
دفعنا؟  لكن أولئك الذين يقومون الآن بتسويق كل هذه الأفكار، فإننا نضيع
it. So we have to, little bit, have a soul searching and find out: "Where am I ?" I have
فيها.  لذلك علينا، قليلًا، أن نبحث بالروح ونكتشف: "أين أنا؟"  يجب أن
to find the truth and I must get to it.
أجد الحقيقة ويجب أن أصل إليها.
This is the time when the whole world has to emancipate, this is the resurrection time
هذا هو الوقت الذي يجب أن يتحرر فيه العالم كله، هذا هو وقت القيامة
or we can call it this is this Last Judgment. But you will be judged by your own Kundalini
أو يمكننا أن نسميه هذا هو يوم الدينونة. ولكن سيتم الحكم عليك من خلال الكونداليني الخاصة بك
who is your Mother. She doesn't trouble you. When you were born your mother took up all
والتي هي والدتك.  إنها لا تزعجك. عندما ولدت، تحملت والدتك كل
the trouble, all the labor pains upon herself, she didn't trouble you. In the same way this
المتاعب، وكل آلام المخاض على عاتقها، ولم تزعجك.  وبنفس الطريقة فإن
Kundalini doesn't trouble you and she is anxiously waiting. I'm Myself amazed the way these days
الكونداليني لا تزعجك وهي تنتظر بفارغ الصبر .  أنا نفسي مندهش من الطريقة التي
the Kundalini is rising. Of course today we have so many people I am sure you all will
ترتفع بها الكونداليني هذه الأيام.  بالطبع لدينا اليوم الكثير من الأشخاص وأنا متأكد من أنكم جميعًا ستدركون
get realization. But in a place like Paris where I never had such hopes thousand people
ذلك.  لكن في مكان مثل باريس، حيث لم يكن لدي مثل هذه الآمال من قبل، فقد تحقق آلاف الأشخاص، لقد
getting realization I was amazed at that and all of them full of joy, laughing, I have
اندهشت من ذلك وكلهم ممتلئون بالفرح، يضحكون،
never seen French women laughing that much. They never laugh normally. I was amazed that
لم أر قط نساء فرنسيات يضحكن بهذا القدر. لا يضحكون بشكل طبيعي أبدًا.  لقد دهشت من أن
all there cheeks were up there, up to their eyes and I said: "What's the matter?"
خدودهم كلها كانت هناك حتى أعينهم فقلت: "ما الأمر؟"
They said, "Mother, we don't know from where this joy is pouring".
فقالوا: يا أماه، لا ندري من أين يتدفق هذا الفرح.
That's the quality of the Spirit that you start feeling so joyous and the joy doesn't
هذه هي صفة الروح التي تبدأ في الشعور بالفرح الشديد والفرح لا
have the duality of happiness and unhappiness. It's singular. You just feel it from within
يحمل ثنائية السعادة والتعاسة. انها المفرد.  أنت فقط تشعر بذلك من داخل
yourself, you enjoy yourself.
نفسك، وتستمتع بنفسك.
Then another quality of the Spirit is that when it comes
ثم صفة أخرى للروح هي أنه عندما يتعلق الأمر
into your attention- the light of the Spirit comes into your attention. Let's supposing
بانتباهك، فإن نور الروح يلفت انتباهك.  لنفترض أن
this room is completely dark, we don't know how we relate to each other, where we are
هذه الغرفة مظلمة تمامًا، ولا نعرف كيف نتواصل مع بعضنا البعض، وأين
sitting, if we start walking we might tumble over other people, we may try to trample some
نجلس، إذا بدأنا في المشي، فقد نتعثر على أشخاص آخرين، وقد نحاول أن ندوس بعض
people. But if there is light you see, you know where you are sitting, where others are
الأشخاص.  ولكن إذا كان هناك ضوء تراه، فأنت تعرف أين تجلس، وأين
sitting, what is your chair, what is their chair. So in that light of Spirit you develop
يجلس الآخرون، وما هو كرسيك، وما هو كرسيهم.  لذلك، في ضوء الروح هذا، فإنك تطور
a new awareness, a new dimension which we call as collective consciousness, which is
وعيًا جديدًا، وهو بُعدًا جديدًا نسميه بالوعي الجماعي، والذي
described by Jung very clearly. Jung has talked about this and that is what happens to you,
وصفه يونج بشكل واضح جدًا.  لقد تحدث يونغ عن هذا وهذا ما يحدث لك،
it is not a false thing that, 'Oh! I am collectively conscious'. No, it happens to you. Means you
ليس من الكذب أن تقول: "أوه!"  أنا واعي بشكل جماعي ”.  لا، هذا يحدث لك.  يعني أنك
can feel the chakras of another person, you can feel what's wrong with him and you know
تستطيع أن تشعر بالشاكرات الخاصة بشخص آخر، ويمكنك أن تشعر بما هو خطأ فيه وتعرف
how to correct it. Under your hand itself the Kundalini will rise, you get the powers,
كيفية تصحيحه.  تحت يدك نفسها سوف ترتفع الكونداليني، وستحصل على القوى،
you get your own powers to raise the Kundalini, give realization. I mean, now I cannot go
وستحصل على قواك الخاصة لرفع الكونداليني، وتحقيق الإدراك.  أعني أنني الآن لا أستطيع الذهاب إلى
all over the places, Sahaja Yogis are doing this work. You all get those powers of raising
كل الأماكن، حيث يقوم Sahaja Yogis بهذا العمل.  أنتم جميعًا تحصلون على تلك القوى لرفع
the Kundalini and giving realizations to others, so that they find their own self, their own
الكونداليني وتحقيق الإنجازات للآخرين، حتى يتمكنوا من العثور على أنفسهم، وروحهم الخاصة
Spirit. So, the absolute knowledge can be only known through self-realization, because
.  لذا، المعرفة المطلقة لا يمكن معرفتها إلا من خلال تحقيق الذات، لأنه
whatever you want to ask like a computer, the answer comes in.
مهما كان ما تريد أن تسأله مثل الكمبيوتر، فإن الإجابة تأتي.
There is somebody who met Me in Paris. He said: "I don't believe in God".
هناك شخص قابلني في باريس. قال: "أنا لا أؤمن بالله".
I said: All right, you ask a question to Me: 'Mother is there God?'. Stretch the hands
فقلت: حسنًا، تسألني سؤالاً: يا أماه هل هناك الله؟  مدّ اليدين
towards Me, ask the question three times.
نحوي، واسأل السؤال ثلاث مرات.
"Mother, what's happening? This cool breeze coming"
"أمي ماذا يحدث؟ هذا النسيم البارد قادم"
I said: "The answer has come, there is God".
قلت: "جاء الجواب، هناك الله".
So absolute knowledge is only possible when you know the Absolute Truth and to have the
لذا فإن المعرفة المطلقة تكون ممكنة فقط عندما تعرف الحقيقة المطلقة ولكي تحصل على
Absolute Truth you have to go to the Absolute Being within you which is your Spirit. So,
الحقيقة المطلقة عليك أن تذهب إلى الكائن المطلق بداخلك وهو روحك.  لذا
it gives you the Truth, it gives you the collective consciousness. The main thing is that you
فهو يمنحك الحقيقة، ويمنحك الوعي الجماعي.  الشيء الرئيسي هو أن
become extremely peaceful personality, you become peace, you emit peace. It's like the
تصبح شخصية مسالمة للغاية، وأن تصبح سلامًا، وتبعث السلام.  إنها مثل
wheel, the wheel at the periphery moving very fast but in the center of the wheel is the
العجلة، العجلة في المحيط تتحرك بسرعة كبيرة ولكن في وسط العجلة يوجد
axis, it has to be silent otherwise cart won't move and you jump onto that point within yourself
المحور، يجب أن تكون صامتة وإلا فلن تتحرك العربة وتقفز إلى تلك النقطة داخل نفسك
where you are completely peaceful with yourself, completely integrated without any tension,
حيث تكون مسالمًا تمامًا مع نفسك  ، متكامل تمامًا بدون أي توتر،
without any problems. And these other ideas of removing tensions, this thing, that thing
بدون أي مشاكل.  وهذه الأفكار الأخرى لإزالة التوترات، هذا الشيء، ذلك الشيء
are all artificial and mental. It cannot be mental, it is beyond mental. When the Kundalini
كلها مصطنعة وعقلية.  لا يمكن أن يكون عقليًا، فهو أبعد من العقلي.  عندما
rises as you see there this is the center in the optic chiasma - Agnya chakra. When
ترتفع الكونداليني كما ترون هناك، هذا هو المركز في التصالب البصري - شقرا أغنيا.  عندما
it crosses that center then these two institutions are sucked in and she passes through the limbic
تعبر هذا المركز، يتم امتصاص هاتين المؤسستين وتمر عبر
area and comes out of your fontanella bone area, which is the actualization of your realization.
المنطقة الحوفية وتخرج من منطقة عظمة اليافوخ ، وهو تحقيق إدراكك.
Also in India, they called it Brahma[...] all kind of nonsense have been done in that name
وفي الهند أيضًا، أطلقوا عليه اسم براهما[...] وقد تم ارتكاب كل أنواع الهراء بهذا الاسم في
everyway, in every religion.
كل مكان وفي كل دين.
So, now for it is absolutely
لذا، فمن الواضح الآن تمامًا
evident for people to see that we have to get to that stage and you have all the properties,
للناس أن يروا أنه يتعين علينا الوصول إلى تلك المرحلة وأن لديك كل الخصائص،
all the possibilities, everything within yourself to get to it.
وكل الإمكانيات، وكل شيء بداخلك للوصول إليها.